Isn’t your brother asking for it?
형이 요구하는 거 아냐?
Just hand it over as soon as possible and it will be over
최대한 빨리 넘겨주시면 끝이에요
There's so much nonsense, you stinky girl
헛소리가 너무 많아 냄새나는 여자야
My brother
내 동생
Do you think I would be happy about being locked up?
내가 갇혀 있으면 기뻐할 것 같아?
Or is it the opposite?
아니면 그 반대인가요?
Are you happy that Go Min-soo turned out like that?
고민수 씨가 이렇게 돼서 기쁘나요?
Just testing it out
그냥 테스트해봐
Where should I stimulate you to react?
당신이 반응하도록 어디에서 자극을 주어야 할까요?
See what your weaknesses are
당신의 약점이 무엇인지 살펴보세요
Is there any secret weapon we can use?
우리가 사용할 수 있는 비밀 무기가 있나요?
Before fully grasping this information
이 정보를 완전히 파악하기 전에
She will never attack
그녀는 결코 공격하지 않을 것이다
It hurts so much. My hand is broken.
너무 아파요 손이 부러졌어요
once she gets the hang of it
그녀가 익숙해지면
you're done
넌 끝났어
Go Min-soo is also a suspect, right?
고민수씨도 피의자죠?
He served more than 30 years in prison as the real murderer
그는 진짜 살인자로 30년 넘게 감옥에서 복역했다.
But the most important thing is the witnesses
하지만 가장 중요한 것은 증인입니다.
She said she saw him kill someone with her own eyes
그녀는 그가 자신의 눈으로 누군가를 죽이는 것을 보았다고 말했습니다
His sister Gao Meishu said
그의 여동생 Gao Meishu는 이렇게 말했습니다.
Do you find it interesting?
흥미로워요?
We will come again next time
다음에 또 올게요
What should I do if my popcorn is so bad?
팝콘이 너무 상하면 어떻게 해야 하나요?
-Teacher- Is popcorn important now?
-선생님- 이제 팝콘이 중요해요?
How are you
어떻게 지내세요
As long as I think of your fragile body
너의 연약한 몸을 생각하는 한
fine
괜찮은
are you injured
당신은 부상을 입었습니까?
How unreasonable
얼마나 불합리한가
I said
나는 말했다
Who are you staring at?
누구를 쳐다보고 있나요?
What did you say
뭐라고 하셨나요
Since you hit someone, you have to apologize first
사람을 때렸으니 먼저 사과부터 해야지
Why are you glaring at someone who is just waiting for peace and suffering?
평화와 고통만 기다리는 사람을 왜 노려보시나요?
Didn't you see that he was wet?
그 사람 젖은 거 못 봤어?
Who told him to stand in the middle of the road and block it?
누가 길 한가운데 서서 막으라고 했나요?
Even a grown man doesn’t know how to be polite to girls
어른 남자도 여자한테 예의를 갖추는 법을 몰라
Do you know him? Why do you call him that?
그 사람을 아시나요? 왜 그렇게 부르나요?
Apologize to him quickly, you bastard
빨리 사과해라 이 새끼야
Why does this stinky girl have such a loud voice?
이 냄새나는 소녀는 왜 그렇게 큰 목소리를 가지고 있습니까?
Why are you meddling in other people's business?
왜 남의 일에 간섭하는 겁니까?
Why are you so careful that I'll beat you up?
내가 때릴 정도로 왜 그렇게 조심하는 거야?
elder brother
형
What's going on? Are you Yanyu?
무슨 일이에요? 당신이 Yanyu입니까?
Brat
애새끼
When did you come back from the United States?
언제 미국에서 돌아오셨나요?
Shang Shu, please say hello to him quickly.
상수 씨, 빨리 그에게 인사해주세요.
The building in our house is in his father's name
우리 집 건물이 아버지 명의로 되어 있어요.
Brother, please apologize first.
형님, 먼저 사과하세요.
What
무엇
Did you just yell at her?
방금 그 사람한테 소리지른 거야?
Do you call her a stinky girl?
그 사람을 냄새나는 여자라고 부르나요?
she is my girlfriend
그녀는 나의 여자 친구 다
What
무엇
I see
알겠어요
This elder brother is also familiar with me
이 형님도 나랑 아는 사이야
But why are his clothes so wet?
그런데 옷은 왜 이렇게 젖어 있는 걸까요?
Excuse me
실례합니다
fine
괜찮은
Sorry I'm sorry
미안해요 미안해요
Teacher, I'll take my leave first.
선생님, 저 먼저 이만 물러가겠습니다.
Good to know
알아 둘만 한
yes
예
- How are you doing? - Of course.
- 잘 지내요? - 물론이죠.
How are you doing?
어떻게 지내세요?
Nothing special
특별한 것은 없습니다
She left the village immediately the night she gave birth to you.
그녀는 당신을 낳은 날 밤에 즉시 마을을 떠났습니다.
Even if I see you crying and your face is red
우는 너를 보고 얼굴이 붉어져도
she also
그녀는 또한
I never hugged you once and then turned around and left
한 번도 안아주지 못하고 돌아서서 떠나버렸어
She sees you as a stain in her life
그녀는 당신을 자기 인생의 얼룩으로 여깁니다.
So don't be curious anymore
그러니 더 이상 궁금해하지 마세요.
Don't even think about her
그 사람에 대해서는 생각도 하지 마세요
really strange
정말 이상해
He was obviously just standing there looking at me
분명 그 사람은 그냥 거기 서서 나를 보고 있었을 거야
At first I wanted to say what he was doing
처음에는 그가 무엇을 하는지 말하고 싶었습니다.
But suddenly I felt sad
그런데 갑자기 슬픈 생각이 들었어요
My heart became inexplicably dull
내 마음은 알 수 없을 정도로 무뎌졌다.
The whole person is depressed
사람 전체가 우울하다
Are you obsessed with him?
당신은 그에게 집착하고 있습니까?
I was serious
나는 진지했다
Maybe there's something really different about him
어쩌면 그 사람에게는 정말 다른 뭔가가 있을 수도 있어요
first time i saw him
내가 그를 처음 봤을 때
I also feel that the mood is a bit subtle
분위기도 좀 오묘한 것 같아요
Should I say it was like this before?
예전에도 그랬다고 해야 하나?
My dad said he wanted to introduce someone to me
아빠가 나한테 누군가를 소개시켜주고 싶다고 했어
He even told me his name
심지어 나한테 자기 이름도 알려줬어
That man's name is Haejun
그 사람 이름은 해준이에요
Is his name Haejun?
이름이 해준이에요?
do you remember
기억 나니
The letter you wrote to me when I was in America
내가 미국에 있을 때 당신이 나에게 쓴 편지
If we get married and have children in the future
만약 우리가 나중에 결혼해서 아이를 낳게 된다면
I’ll name him Haejun
이름은 해준이라고 할게요
I don’t know if it’s because of this
이것 때문인지는 모르겠지만
I have special feelings for him
나는 그 사람에 대해 특별한 감정을 가지고 있습니다
but
하지만
Very strange
아주 이상한
No wonder I didn't like her from the beginning
당연하지 난 처음부터 그 사람을 좋아하지 않았어
Did you eat
밥은 먹었 니
Do you know me
나를 아시나요?
Can't we just start getting to know each other now?
이제부터 서로 알아가면 안 될까요?
Since it's your first time here, I'll give you a cup of tea.
처음 오시니까 차 한잔 드릴께요.
That's what I'm best at
그게 내가 제일 잘하는 거야
Oh my God, are you crazy?
맙소사, 미쳤어?
Why break the egg?
계란을 깨는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Don’t you know how to drink Shuanghe tea?
쌍허차 마시는 법을 모르시나요?
You don't care how I want to drink it
내가 어떻게 마시고 싶은지 넌 상관하지 않아
Wait for me and I'll make you another cup
기다리면 한 잔 더 만들어줄게
No, it's okay
아니 괜찮아
I can't stand someone cracking the egg
나는 누군가가 계란을 깨는 것을 참을 수 없다
This is how you want to drink
이렇게 마시고 싶다
- Good mouth open - No need
- 입 벌리기 좋음 - 필요 없음
I will do it myself
내가 직접 할게
It doesn't matter, I'll take it all, just relax
상관없어 다 내가 감당할게 그냥 편히 쉬어
Because I feel very uncomfortable
기분이 매우 불편하기 때문에
Oh my god
맙소사
There
거기
I think in the future
내 생각엔 앞으로도
I should come here often
여기 자주 와야겠어요
Really
정말
so
그래서
I hope you can talk to me without any problem
아무 문제 없이 얘기할 수 있었으면 좋겠어
Physical contact or interference in my affairs
내 일에 신체적 접촉이나 간섭
You don’t need to recommend meals to me.
나에게 식사를 추천할 필요는 없습니다.
Treat me as a stranger as much as possible and ignore me
나를 최대한 낯선 사람으로 대하고 무시하라
Even though we didn’t know each other before
예전에는 서로 몰랐는데도
I know I will work hard
나는 열심히 일할 것을 안다.
good
좋은
I can't stand it
나는 그것을 참을 수 없다
Look how she does whatever she wants
그녀가 원하는 것은 무엇이든 어떻게 하는지 보세요
No wonder they leave their children alone
그들이 아이들을 혼자 두는 것도 당연합니다
It's a stranger anyway
어쨌든 낯선 사람이야
we are just strangers
우리는 단지 낯선 사람일 뿐이에요
after that night
그날 밤 이후
time flies
시간은 흐른다
But the amazing thing is
그런데 놀라운 점은
The village remains unchanged
마을은 변함이 없다
How on earth do you do things?
도대체 어떻게 일을 하시나요?
It’s been half a month, let alone catching the culprit.
범인 잡기는커녕 보름이 지났다.
Not even a single suspect has been identified.
용의자는 단 한 명도 확인되지 않았습니다.
Do you think it makes sense?
말이 된다고 생각하시나요?
talk
말하다
“Incompetent and irresponsible”
“무능하고 무책임하다”
"Chief of Ushii Police Station"
"우시이 경찰서장"
hateful
증오스러운
"Before promotion review of Gyeonggi Province Police Chief"
"경기지방경찰청장 승진심사 전"
"Doubted as to whether he is not qualified"
"자격이 없는지 의심스럽다"
Hey Hyun Kyu
안녕하세요 현규님
are you
당신은
Deliberately trying to block my future
일부러 내 미래를 막으려 해
I'm very sorry
나는 매우 미안 해요
My future is your future
나의 미래는 당신의 미래입니다
Wake me up
나를 깨워줘
Show me the results
결과를 보여주세요
Gotta catch a guy within a week
일주일 안에 남자를 잡아야 해
bring it to me
나에게 가져 와봐
Don't do something stupid
멍청한 짓은 하지마
Why are you still standing there? Hurry up and get out.
왜 아직도 거기 서 있나요 어서 나가세요
Go investigate
조사하러 가세요
where did you just go
방금 어디 갔어?
Why didn't you wake me up and come with you?
왜 나를 깨워서 우리와 함께 가지 않았나요?
Are you having nightmares again?
또 악몽을 꾸나요?
What the hell is this dream?
도대체 이 꿈은 뭐죠?
How come I have the same dream for a week in a row?
왜 일주일 연속 같은 꿈을 꾼 걸까요?
Are you really not going to tell me?
정말 나한테 말 안 할 거야?
Then where were you just now?
그럼 지금은 어디에 있었나요?
Today is
오늘은
The day Baek Yoo-seob was discharged from the hospital
백유섭이 퇴원한 날
I just happened to have something to ask him.
방금 그 사람한테 물어볼 게 있어서 그랬어요.
Just drop by
그냥 들르세요
Uncle should also know by now
삼촌도 이제 알았을텐데
Who died in this village?
이 마을에서는 누가 죽었나요?
I know you have nothing to do with the murder.
나는 당신이 살인과 관련이 없다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
But with the two victims
하지만 피해자 2명과 함께
People with whom you have the most frequent contact
가장 자주 연락하는 사람들
It’s not Baek Hee-seop, it’s you
백희섭이 아니라 너야
Is there anything you can share with me?
나와 공유할 수 있는 것이 있나요?
The reason why Li Zhuying returned to the village
리주잉이 마을로 돌아온 이유
It’s because of Baek Yoo Seop
백유섭 때문이야
They originally agreed to leave together
그들은 원래 함께 떠나기로 합의했습니다
She will come here in the first place
그녀는 우선 여기로 올 것이다
It was also because of Baek Yoo Seob’s help.
그것도 백유섭의 도움 덕분이었다.
I think
제 생각에는
They may not just be a simple relationship between seniors and juniors
단순한 선후배 사이의 관계가 아닐 수도 있다.
Then why didn't he leave?
그렇다면 그는 왜 떠나지 않았는가?
Because a few days later
왜냐면 며칠 뒤에
It happens to be the death anniversary of Baek Yoo-seop’s parents
마침 백유섭 부모님의 기일이다.
If you want to avoid police eyes and ears, leave
경찰의 눈과 귀를 피하고 싶다면 떠나라
I don’t know when I can come back again
언제 다시 올 수 있을지 모르겠어
At least he wanted to spend more time with his brother that day
적어도 그 사람은 그날 형과 더 많은 시간을 보내고 싶었어요
So I decided to hide in the village for those few days.
그래서 나는 그 며칠 동안 마을에 숨어 있기로 결정했습니다.
But where they are hiding
하지만 그들이 어디에 숨어 있는지
It happens to be an abandoned house
버려진 집이군요
- Could it be - That's right
- 그럴 수도 있지 - 그렇죠
It was the abandoned house where Li Jingai was found.
리징가이가 발견된 곳은 버려진 집이었습니다.
The night of the incident
사건이 일어난 밤
She seems to have gone to find us too
그 사람도 우리를 찾으러 간 것 같아
How are you
어떻게 지내세요
That day when we were with Li Jingai
리징가이와 함께 있던 그날
She seems to be secretly following Baek Yoo Seob
백유섭을 몰래 따라다니는 것 같다
What to wear?
무엇을 입어야할지?
Anyway, the three of them became friends
아무튼 세 사람은 친해졌어요
And Li Jingai also helped keep it secret
그리고 Li Jingai도 이 사실을 비밀로 유지하는 데 도움을 주었습니다.
I'm also curious
나도 궁금해
After she listened to our story
그녀가 우리 이야기를 듣고 난 후
Expressing that he wants to help with something
뭔가 도움을 주고 싶다고 표현하기
She asked if we needed anything
그녀는 우리에게 필요한 것이 있는지 물었습니다.
she may be
그녀는 아마도
You go there just to get something for us.
당신은 우리를 위해 뭔가를 얻으러 거기로 갑니다.
If I hadn't gone to Seoul then
그때 서울에 가지 않았더라면
If we hadn't missed it
우리가 놓치지 않았더라면
can protect the two of them
두 사람을 지켜줄 수 있어
What puzzles me most during this period is
이 기간 동안 나를 가장 당황하게 만드는 것은
That's the sentence
그 문장이에요
"Women who read are dangerous"
"읽는 여자는 위험하다"
What does this sentence mean?
이 문장은 무엇을 의미하나요?
Why did the prisoner write this sentence specifically?
죄수는 왜 이 문장을 구체적으로 썼을까요?
stay with the victim
피해자와 함께 있어라
Li Zhuying does have a book at hand
Li Zhuying은 손에 책을 가지고 있습니다.
But
하지만
Only Lee Joo Young has it
이주영만이 가지고 있다
Li Jingai doesn’t have such a thing
리진가이는 그런거 없어요
That's what I originally thought
원래 그렇게 생각했는데
The reason why Li Jingai went to that abandoned house that night
그날 밤 이정개이가 그 버려진 집에 간 이유
It’s to send Baek Yoo-seop away
백유섭을 보내기 위해서다
The only thing I need from Lee Joo Young
이주영한테 딱 필요한 건
what do you think that would be
그게 어떨 것 같아?
It turns out to be a book
책으로 나오네요
Thus
따라서
The victims really have something in common
피해자들에겐 공통점이 있다
That's the book in their hands
그게 그 사람들 손에 있는 책이야
Maybe this is a warning
어쩌면 이건 경고일지도 몰라
But where did those books go?
그런데 그 책들은 어디로 갔나요?
Why didn't I see it at the crime scene?
왜 범죄 현장에서 보지 못했습니까?
If the prisoner notices
죄수가 눈치채면
If you write this kind of sentence
이런 문장을 쓰면
Then it's possible that they were taken away by prisoners.
그렇다면 포로들에게 끌려갔을 가능성도 있다.
Although I don’t know the reason for doing this
비록 내가 이렇게 하는 이유를 알지 못하더라도
Brother that one
형 그거요
I know very well the terms we negotiated
나는 우리가 협상한 조건을 아주 잘 알고 있다
I also know I can only get in and out of the garage but
차고에만 드나들 수 있다는 것도 알고 있지만
Why are you making such a disgusting gasping sound?
왜 이렇게 역겨운 헐떡거리는 소리를 내는 걸까요?
I'm dying. I'm in a hurry to get a big size.
죽겠다.. 급하게 빅사이즈 구해요.
- Wait for me. - No.
- 기다려요 - 아니
Yunying quickly cleaned these up
윤잉이는 빨리 이것들을 치웠어요
where is the toilet
화장실은 어디입니까
Occasionally this happens
가끔 이런 일이 발생합니다
I forgot that his stomach is weak
그 사람 위장이 약한 걸 깜빡했네
Just do this
그냥 이렇게 하세요
He spends almost all day in the garage
그는 거의 하루 종일 차고에서 시간을 보낸다
If he is not even allowed to use the toilet
화장실 사용조차 허락되지 않는 경우
This is too harsh on our heroes.
이것은 우리 영웅들에게 너무 가혹한 일입니다.
But why is it a book?
그런데 왜 책인가?
"Women who read are dangerous"
"읽는 여자는 위험하다"
Publishing books is my job
책 출판이 내 직업이다
Is this really all a coincidence?
정말 이 모든 것이 우연일까요?
At the end of the day, my mom also wanted to be a writer who wrote books.
결국 엄마도 책을 쓰는 작가가 되고 싶었어요.
And Gao Meishu is too
가오메이슈도 그렇고
i always think
나는 항상 생각한다
Maybe all this is not just a coincidence
어쩌면 이 모든 게 단순한 우연은 아닐지도 몰라
Then what are you going to do for me?
그러면 나를 위해 무엇을 해줄 건가요?
What
무엇
I've already paid for your tuition.
나는 이미 당신의 수업료를 지불했습니다.
So what are you going to do for me?
그럼 당신은 나를 위해 무엇을 해줄 건가요?
Didn’t you also steal dad’s private money?
너도 아빠 사돈 훔친거 아니었어?
Why is stolen money not money?
훔친 돈은 왜 돈이 아닌가?
Looks like it won’t work anymore. Give it back to me.
더 이상 작동하지 않을 것 같습니다. 다시 돌려주세요.
Dad Lee Soon Ae
아빠 이순애
What do you want me to do
내가 무엇을 하기를 원하시나요?
my name
내 이름
If you become a novelist in the future
나중에 소설가가 된다면
I hope you can be in the corner of the book
책 한구석에 네가 있기를 바라
write my name
내 이름을 써
What's that?
그게 뭐야?
What kind of stinky girl could she be?
그녀는 어떤 냄새 나는 소녀가 될 수 있습니까?
this is amazing
이거 엄청나 네
Feed one person at most
최대 한 명에게 먹이세요.
Neither will live to be a hundred years old
둘 다 백 살까지 살지 못할 것이다
But books can last forever
하지만 책은 영원히 지속될 수 있다
So if you are willing to write my name in the book
그러니 당신이 책에 내 이름을 써줄 의향이 있다면
Everyone will know this person Li Jingai
모두가 이 사람을 알게 될 것입니다 Li Jingai
once lived in this world
한때 이 세상에 살았지
This way it will be famous forever
이렇게 하면 영원히 유명해질 거야
Is this so happy?
이게 그렇게 행복한 걸까요?
Of course I'm happy
물론 기쁘다
Hey, even after a thousand years
야, 천년이 지나도
I can also be known to the world as Li Jingai
나는 또한 Li Jingai로 세상에 알려질 수 있습니다
Your sister will soon become a famous person
네 여동생은 곧 유명인이 될 거야
Do you dare to laugh?
감히 웃을 수 있나요?
Hello to the Chinese teacher from the opposite house
안녕하세요 반대편 집 중국어 선생님 입니다
He also praised me for feeling very good
그 분도 기분이 너무 좋다고 칭찬해 주셨어요
She also said that even if she is not Miss Korea,
미스코리아가 아니더라도
There is also a way to go on TV
TV에 나오는 방법도 있어요
Soonae if I become very famous
순애 내가 엄청 유명해지면
i will be all over the world
나는 전 세계에 있을 거야
I leave my footprints in every corner
구석구석에 발자국을 남기고
Dear villagers in Niujingli,
친애하는 뉴징리 마을 주민 여러분,
The eldest daughter of Lee Hyung Man and Park Ok Ja
이형만과 박옥자의 큰딸
Ms. Lee Kyung-ae
이경애씨
She lived a life full of fun
그녀는 재미로 가득한 삶을 살았습니다
like this
이와 같이
So you must remember to write
그러니 꼭 기억해서 써야 해요
Do you understand
이해했나요
You don't answer me
당신은 나에게 대답하지 않습니다
- Then I'll take this back. - No.
- 그럼 이건 다시 가져갈게요 - 아니
Do you know how many bottles of wine these can buy?
이걸로 몇 병의 와인을 살 수 있는지 아시나요?
Did you see the bookstore on the way here?
여기 오는 길에 서점 보셨나요?
I saw that Go Mi-sook is actually a novelist
고미숙 씨가 실제로 소설가인 걸 봤어요.
It really scared me
정말 무서웠어요
It's amazing
놀랍다
Hey, I heard that Go Mi-sook became a novelist.
안녕하세요, 고미숙 씨가 소설가가 되었다고 들었습니다.
Really
정말
"To Y"
"Y에게"
"Sometimes I feel lonely"
"가끔 외로움을 느껴요"
"I can imagine"
"내가 상상할 수있는"
“That one is equally unpopular”
“그 사람도 마찬가지로 인기가 없어요”
"My secret little door hidden somewhere"
"어딘가에 숨겨져 있는 나의 비밀의 작은 문"
I missed
나는 그리워했다
I really didn't expect it would be this time
정말 이번에가 될 거라고는 예상하지 못했어요
"Congratulations"
"축하해요"
"The birth of a genius female high school novelist"
"천재 여고 소설가의 탄생"
"New products this year, new products this year"
"올해 신제품, 올해 신제품"
"Changes in Publishing"
"출판의 변화"
"The birth of a 19-year-old female high school novelist"
"19세 여고생 소설가의 탄생"
"Appeared like a comet in the literary world"
"문학계에 혜성처럼 나타났다"
“little wine”
“작은 와인”
Is it written there about Gao Meishu from our school?
거기에 우리 학교의 가오메이슈에 대한 글이 적혀 있나요?
Gao Meishu in our class is absolutely true
우리 반의 Gao Meishu는 절대적으로 사실입니다
A newspaper company wanted to interview her
한 신문사가 그녀를 인터뷰하고 싶어했어요
Asked if I could bring publishing house staff and reporters with me
출판사 직원과 기자들을 데리고 와도 되냐고 물으셨어요
No problem, right?
문제 없어요, 그렇죠?
Do I need to fix my hair?
머리를 고쳐야 하나요?
Tell me why until I finish writing this book
내가 이 책을 다 쓸 때까지 이유를 말해주세요.
She had never mentioned this to the school before
그녀는 이전에 학교에 이 이야기를 한 적이 없었습니다.
She really fooled everyone
그녀는 정말로 모두를 속였습니다
She suddenly brought the book over and shocked me.
그녀는 갑자기 책을 가져와서 나에게 충격을 주었다.
That's outrageous
그건 터무니없는 일이야
how come
어쩌다
I want to help my mother realize her dream that she couldn't realize
어머니가 이루지 못한 꿈을 이루도록 돕고 싶습니다.
I heard she once dreamed of becoming a novelist
한때 소설가를 꿈꿨다고 들었는데
just like me
나처럼
She was once a young person who was passionate about literature
그녀는 한때 문학에 열정을 품은 청년이었습니다.
He is also my junior college student
그 사람도 내 단기 대학생이야
Oh my God, it turns out she inherited your talent.
맙소사, 그녀가 당신의 재능을 물려받았다는 사실이 밝혀졌습니다.
- That's true - That's a prize
- 그렇군요 - 상이군요
My daughter is better than me
내 딸이 나보다 낫다
After all, this is my first work
그러고보니 이게 내 첫 작품이구나
If you want to be on par with your mother, you still have a long way to go.
어머니와 동등해지고 싶다면 아직 갈 길이 멀다.
But I hope this is a special gift
하지만 이건 특별한 선물이길 바라
Because it will be her birthday soon
왜냐면 곧 그 사람 생일이거든
is that so
그렇습니까?
Oh, happy birthday to you
아, 생일 축하해
The relationship between mother and daughter is really harmonious.
엄마와 딸의 관계는 정말 조화롭습니다.
this will be the best gift
이건 최고의 선물이 될 거야
First day on the shelves in bookstores in Seoul
서울 서점 진열 첫날
received a warm response
뜨거운 반응을 받았습니다
There is even a trend of becoming a best-selling book
베스트셀러가 되는 추세도 있다.
- Really? - That's great.
- 정말요? - 정말 좋아요.
It is also a great joy for us at Ushii High School
우시이 고등학교에 있는 것은 우리에게도 큰 기쁨입니다
This is the first time since the establishment of the school
개교 이래 처음 있는 일이다.
if i knew in advance
내가 미리 알았더라면
Will definitely hang a big banner in the school
학교에 꼭 큰 현수막을 걸어 놓을 거예요
Takami tree
다카미 나무
talk to me
나에게 말을 걸어
how could you do such a thing
어떻게 그런 일을 할 수 있니?
tell me why
이유를 말해줘
How could you steal
어떻게 훔칠 수 있니?
what did i steal
내가 뭘 훔쳤지?
what are you saying
당신이 무슨 말을하는거야
my novel
내 소설
Don't lie shamelessly in front of me
내 앞에서 뻔뻔하게 거짓말하지 마
what your novel
당신의 소설은 무엇입니까?
I really don't know what you are talking about
나는 정말로 당신이 무슨 말을 하는지 모르겠어요
Mi-sook please
미숙아 제발
Have you been having a hard time lately?
최근에 힘든 일이 있었나요?
Then you can't make trouble with Shun Ai unreasonably.
그러면 순아이에게 무리하게 문제를 일으킬 수는 없습니다.
How many times did you think you could help me with my composition assignments?
내 작곡 과제를 도와줄 수 있다고 몇 번이나 생각하셨나요?
Do you mistakenly think that what I wrote is yours?
내가 쓴 글이 당신의 것이라고 잘못 생각하는 건가요?
I didn't expect you to be so bad
네가 그렇게 나쁠 줄은 몰랐어
I won't tolerate it
나는 그것을 용납하지 않을 것이다
I want to make the truth known to the world
진실을 세상에 알리고 싶다
What you asked me to do
당신이 나에게 요청한 것
All will be told
다 말해줄게
Why are you so annoying Soon Ae?
순애야 왜이렇게 짜증나?
Then I have to take measures
그럼 조치를 취해야지
What a trouble
정말 문제다
you
너
Is there any evidence?
증거가 있나요?
Lost notebook?
노트북을 분실하셨나요?
Does anyone know if you wrote that?
당신이 그렇게 썼다면 아는 사람 있나요?
No matter what, your efforts will be in vain
아무리 노력해도 헛수고가 될 것이다
So just wait and see.
그러니 기다려 보세요.
Keep making trouble
계속 문제를 일으키세요
Be careful to end up like your sister Shun Ai
언니 슌아이처럼 되지 않도록 조심하세요
ok
좋아요
I once wanted a woman who likes to read books
한때는 책 읽는 걸 좋아하는 여자를 원했는데
Why do they always look like that?
왜 그들은 항상 그렇게 보일까요?
What
무엇
Act like you are the protagonist
당신이 주인공인 것처럼 행동하세요
Pretend to be smart and know everything
똑똑한 척 모든 것을 아는 척
I just know how to read a few words on paper
나는 단지 종이에 적힌 몇 단어를 읽는 방법을 알고 있을 뿐입니다.
As if I am such a unique existence
마치 내가 이렇게 독특한 존재인 것처럼
It’s really unpleasant to look at
보기에 정말 안쓰럽다
But after trying it I found
그런데 사용해본 결과 알게 된 사실은
Quite interesting
꽤 흥미로운
It's not too late now
이제 늦지 않았어
There's still time to save it
아직 저장할 시간이 있어요
Gao Meishu is right
가오메이슈 말이 맞다
I have no evidence, who will believe me?
증거도 없는데 누가 믿겠어요?
The notebook has disappeared without a trace
노트가 흔적도 없이 사라졌어요
The book has also been published
책도 출간됐어요
The only person who sees me writing
내가 글을 쓰는 것을 본 유일한 사람
only my sister
내 여동생뿐이야
but she has
하지만 그녀는
Why do you give up without even trying?
왜 노력도 하지 않고 포기하는 걸까요?
If Gao Mi-sook says no, will it be over?
가오미숙이 거절하면 끝나는 걸까?
Because Go Mi-sook said otherwise
고미숙이 다르게 말했으니까
Everyone will believe her
모두가 그녀를 믿을 것이다
If this matter gets too big
이 문제가 너무 커지면
My parents will know too
부모님도 알겠지
But my parents
하지만 부모님은
Even if he knew I wrote novels, he wouldn't be proud of it
내가 소설을 쓴다는 걸 알더라도 그 사람은 자랑스러워하지 않을 거예요.
Instead, it will only make them work harder.
대신, 그것은 그들이 더 열심히 일하게 만들 뿐입니다.
as long as i give up
내가 포기하는 한
As long as I swallow my anger
내가 분노를 삼키는 한
Maybe you can just pretend that nothing happened
어쩌면 아무 일도 일어나지 않은 척 할 수도 있겠네요
This is possible for everyone
이것은 누구에게나 가능하다
It will be better
좋아질거야
turn out to be
것으로 밝혀지다
Mom gave up in this mood
엄마는 이 기분에 포기했어요
But this won't work
하지만 이건 작동하지 않을 거야
Cheer up Lee Soon Ae
이순애님 힘내세요
Is your family only composed of mom and dad?
당신의 가족은 엄마, 아빠로만 구성되어 있나요?
There are also Wufu and my sister.
Wufu와 내 여동생도 있습니다.
no
아니요
Is it just Wufu and sister?
우푸와 언니뿐인가요?
Otherwise, who else
그렇지 않으면 누가
Think about it as if you have other family members
다른 가족이 있는 것처럼 생각해보세요.
that person
저 사람
My favorite novel written by you in the world
당신이 쓴 세상에서 내가 가장 좋아하는 소설
That person hopes to be in this world
그 사람은 이 세상에 있기를 바라고 있어
In favorite novel
좋아하는 소설에
Write your name and not someone else's
다른 사람의 이름이 아닌 자신의 이름을 쓰세요
That person wants you to borrow that novel
그 사람이 그 소설을 빌려달라고 하네
Become a truly handsome novelist
정말 멋진 소설가가 되어보세요
You can also read your favorite books
좋아하는 책도 읽을 수 있어요
listen to music to your heart's content
마음껏 음악을 들어라
While sipping hot coffee
따뜻한 커피를 마시면서
I hope you don't have to give up anything anymore
더 이상 아무것도 포기하지 않길 바라요
You can do what you want
너가 원하는 것을 할수있어
Maybe someone is so desperate to
어쩌면 누군가는 너무 절박해서
can you live like this
너는 이렇게 살 수 있니?
do you know
당신은 알고 있나요
come on in
들어와
- Behave yourself - Where are you going?
- 행동해라 - 어디로 가나요?
Soon Ae
순애
You know in Moon Night nightclub
Moon Night 나이트클럽에 있는 거 알지?
Do you occasionally go to the Hallasan Band where you sing as a resident?
레지던트로 노래하는 한라산밴드에 가끔 가시나요?
Although some people say that they
어떤 사람들은 그렇다고 말하지만
Is it imitating the Changbai Mountain Band?
장백산악단을 흉내낸 것인가?
But I still respect those brothers very much
하지만 나는 아직도 그 형제들을 매우 존경한다.
Especially the drummer brother inside
특히 안에 있는 드러머 형이
But one day that brother
그런데 어느 날 그 형이
A big crisis has come
큰 위기가 찾아왔다
what crisis
무슨 위기인가
Have loose bowels
장이 느슨하다
Should I endure it until death or go to the toilet alive?
죽을 때까지 참아야 할까, 아니면 살아서 화장실에 가야 할까?
He must make a choice immediately
그는 즉시 선택을 해야 한다
At this time, the brother glanced around
이때 형이 주위를 둘러보았다.
Just a small performance in a village nightclub
마을 나이트클럽에서의 작은 공연
There won't be any problem if you interrupt for a while.
잠시 방해를 해도 문제가 되지 않습니다.
But that brother did it for the audience
그런데 그 형이 관객을 위해서 한 거야
Hold his position until the end
끝까지 그 자리를 지켜라
Does that mean he was pulled out where he was?
그 말은 그가 있던 곳으로 끌려갔다는 뜻인가요?
yes
예
What's the takeaway from this sordid story?
이 더러운 이야기에서 얻을 수 있는 점은 무엇입니까?
Now that it has started
이제 시작되었으니
The result should be made
결과가 나와야지
Isn’t that novel Shun Ai You?
그 소설은 순아이유(Shun Ai You) 아닌가요?
Then you should try your best to hold it until the end.
그렇다면 끝까지 버틸 수 있도록 최선을 다해야 합니다.
I'm waving like crazy next to you to cheer you on
나는 당신을 응원하기 위해 당신 옆에서 미친 듯이 손을 흔들고 있습니다
How can you give up, right?
어떻게 포기할 수 있죠?
How can you forget that I'm still here?
내가 아직 여기 있다는 걸 어떻게 잊을 수 있나요?
You stinky girl
냄새나는 여자야
Mother
어머니
How could I not be proud of you?
내가 어떻게 당신을 자랑스러워하지 않을 수 있겠습니까?
- What - you know?
- 당신이 알고?
When your sister said she wanted to be Miss Korea
언니가 미스코리아가 되고 싶다고 했을 때
When I said I wanted to be a singer
가수가 되고 싶다고 했을 때
I never promised her once
나는 그녀에게 한 번도 약속한 적이 없다.
Do you know how much I regret it?
내가 얼마나 후회하는지 알아?
Stand tall and fight for your return, you know?
당당하게 서서 당신의 귀환을 위해 싸우세요, 아시죠?
Let's go
갑시다
what
무엇
How many people did you let know about this?
이 사실을 몇 명에게 알렸나요?
Bad things should be known to as many people as possible
나쁜 일은 가능한 한 많은 사람에게 알려야 한다
Only then will bad women be punished
그래야만 나쁜 여자가 벌을 받을 것이다
That's a road I'm very familiar with
그 길은 나에게 매우 익숙한 길이다
About 30 years in the future
앞으로 30년 정도
It's my way to work in a publishing house
출판사에서 일하는 방식이에요
Although this is me
이게 나인데도
It was the first time I went there with my mother.
어머니와 함께 처음 가본 곳이었습니다.
And there
거기
There are very familiar faces that I have known for a long time
오랫동안 알고 지냈던 아주 낯익은 얼굴들이 있어요
The real owner of the novel has arrived
소설의 진짜 주인이 나타났다
Do you want to have a formal talk?
정식으로 얘기하고 싶나요?
That's really not the case
정말 그렇지 않아요
They colluded to do this.
그들은 이것을 하기 위해 공모했습니다.
what on earth do you want
도대체 뭘 원하는 거야?
This is no small matter
이것은 작은 문제가 아니다
This book has been published
이 책이 출판되었습니다
National Bookstore
국립서점
They're all being sold under my name and photo.
전부 내 이름과 사진으로 판매되고 있어요.
If things get serious, can you take responsibility?
일이 심각해지면 책임을 질 수 있나요?
And do you have evidence?
그리고 증거가 있나요?
Not to mention that your parents are still grieving the loss of their daughter.
당신의 부모님이 여전히 딸을 잃은 슬픔에 잠겨 있다는 사실은 말할 것도 없습니다.
Is it really okay for you to make trouble like this?
정말 이렇게 말썽을 피우는 것이 괜찮은 걸까요?
Senior, let’s wait until the lawyer comes to talk.
선배님, 변호사가 얘기하실 때까지 기다리세요.
Prisoners are always clamoring for evidence.
죄수들은 항상 증거를 요구합니다.
Evidence from your mouth
입에서 나온 증거
If it refers to the notebook that was stolen by you
당신이 훔친 노트북을 가리키는 경우
That doesn't
그렇지 않습니다
But you thought writing a novel
하지만 당신은 소설을 쓴다고 생각했나요?
Is just a notebook enough?
노트북만으로도 충분합니까?
This is a novel I started writing two years ago
2년 전부터 쓰기 시작한 소설이에요
There are articles in it that I wrote and then deleted.
거기에 제가 썼다가 삭제한 글도 있어요.
Thinking about what words to use and what meanings to give them
어떤 단어를 사용할지, 어떤 의미를 부여할지 생각하기
What is written in the essay
에세이에 쓰여진 내용
There are also chapters that I originally wanted to include but later deleted.
원래 포함하고 싶었지만 나중에 삭제한 챕터도 있습니다.
it's all inside
다 안에 있어요
You'll understand once you see it
한번 보시면 이해가 되실 겁니다
Once you see it, you will know that you will definitely do it.
한번 보시면, 반드시 하게 되실 거라는 걸 아실 겁니다.
Those were her notes after reading my novel
그건 그녀가 내 소설을 읽은 후 메모한 것이었습니다.
fabricated by oneself
스스로 조작한 것
I can answer all the questions
나는 모든 질문에 답할 수 있다
All about the novel
소설에 관한 모든 것
I can answer them all
다 대답해줄 수 있어
But you can't do it
하지만 넌 할 수 없어
Takami tree
다카미 나무
Senior, what are you doing?
선배, 뭐하세요?
She said she would know after seeing it
해보면 알겠다고 하더군요
Of course it depends
물론 상황에 따라 다릅니다
and ask her
그리고 그녀에게 물어보세요
I also have many curious things
저도 궁금한게 많아요
Mother
어머니
yes
예
The quantity published so far is planned to be recycled
현재까지 발행된 수량은 재활용 예정입니다.
Interviews with writers have also been cancelled.
작가와의 인터뷰도 취소됐다.
Will not be republished anytime soon
조만간 다시 출판되지 않을 예정입니다.
The content of the novel will not be changed
소설의 내용은 바뀌지 않습니다
Instead, change the author’s name and novel cover
대신 작가 이름과 소설 표지를 바꾸세요
Yes
예
Please arrange a time for the interview then.
그럼 인터뷰 시간을 정해주세요.
OK, thanks
알았어 고마워
republished in mom's name
엄마 이름으로 다시 출판됨
The first page of the novel
소설의 첫 페이지
She specifically requested that this sentence be added.
그녀는 특별히 이 문장을 추가해 달라고 요청했습니다.
"This novel"
"이 소설"
"Dedicated to those who live in the cow well"
"소우물에 사는 이들에게 바친다"
"The eldest daughter of Lee Hyung Man and Park Ok Ja"
"이형만과 박옥자의 큰딸"
"Li Jingai"
"리징가이"
At the same time, I also learned a little secret
동시에 나는 작은 비밀도 배웠다.
I have a question
질문이 있어요
"To Y"
"Y에게"
Who is Y?
Y는 누구입니까?
yes
예
The name of the friend I want to see in the future
앞으로 만나고 싶은 친구의 이름
She said it was
그녀는 그랬다고 했어
If she gives birth to a daughter in the future
만약 나중에 딸을 낳게 된다면
The first English letter of the name I want to give her
그녀에게 주고 싶은 이름의 첫 번째 영문 글자
For example, Yunying’s Y
예를 들어 윤잉의 Y
Yunying thank you
윤잉님 감사합니다
Thanks to you I can get my novel back
덕분에 내 소설을 다시 찾을 수 있게 됐어요
Me too
저도요
It's all thanks to you
다 네 덕분이야
this day
오늘
really happy
정말 행복합니다
Never been so perfect in my life
내 인생에서 이렇게 완벽했던 적은 없었어
happy day
행복한 날
Mom can't
엄마는 못해
Mother
어머니
If you want to do such an unpopular thing
이런 인기 없는 짓을 하고 싶다면
What else are you reading?
또 무엇을 읽고 있나요?
It's better to tear them all up
다 찢어버리는 게 낫지
Mom, I know I was wrong
엄마, 제가 틀렸다는 걸 알아요
"A gift to me"
"나에게 주는 선물"
"Help me realize my unfulfilled dreams."
"내가 이루지 못한 꿈을 실현할 수 있도록 도와주세요."
What a joke
좋은 농담 이었어
Give birth to a worthless daughter like you
너같이 쓸모없는 딸을 낳아라
is my shame
내 부끄러운 일이야
do you know
당신은 알고 있나요
Mother
어머니
what are you doing here
여기서 뭐해?
I see you are sleeping soundly
푹 자고 있는 걸 보니
Are you again
또 당신인가요?
Can I sit next to you? I'm a little scared.
옆에 앉아도 될까요 조금 겁이 나네요
This is much better
이게 훨씬 낫다
A day of running around in Seoul
서울을 뛰어다니는 하루
I thought you would be tired and have a good night's sleep
피곤해서 푹 잘 수 있을 줄 알았는데
And things turned out well
그리고 일이 잘 풀렸어요
That is to say
즉 말하자면
I thought so too
나도 그렇게 생각했어
It's like I drank hundreds of bottles of soda
소다수백병을 마신거같아
Put me under Gao Meishu's oppression
나를 Gao Meishu의 억압 아래에 두십시오
The pain accumulated for 6 years is clearly cleansed
6년 동안 쌓인 아픔이 말끔히 씻어지네요
But that nightmare is not over
하지만 그 악몽은 끝나지 않았습니다
What the hell is this dream?
도대체 이 꿈은 뭐죠?
Are you really not going to tell me?
정말 나한테 말 안 할 거야?
That seemed to happen not long ago
그런 일이 일어난 지 얼마 되지 않은 것 같았어요
I took a time machine and went back to the future
타임머신을 타고 미래로 돌아갔어
parents
부모
They all changed into what I imagined
모두 내가 상상했던 모습으로 변해버렸어
Everything looks great
모든 것이 좋아 보인다
Wouldn't that be great? What's wrong?
정말 좋지 않을까요? 무엇이 문제인가요?
But
하지만
never mind
괜찮아요
Are you actually showing off your skills at this time?
지금 이 순간 정말 실력을 뽐내고 계시나요?
It's nothing, just a weird dream
아무것도 아니야 그냥 이상한 꿈일 뿐이야
Like it's boring and pointless
지루하고 무의미한 것처럼
Weird mess of a movie
영화의 이상한 혼란
I actually went to see a movie a few days ago
사실 며칠 전에 영화를 보러 갔었어요
I also met my mother there
나도 거기서 엄마를 만났어
That feeling is strange
그 느낌이 이상해요
What it feels like to meet the person who abandoned me
나를 버린 사람을 만나는 느낌
one year from now
지금부터 1년
The person who left after giving birth to me
나를 낳고 떠난 사람
you said
당신은 말했다
It's not a dream, it's reality
꿈이 아니고 현실이에요
Just treat it as a dream?
그냥 꿈으로만 다루나요?
As long as I want to find her no matter what
무슨 일이 있어도 그녀를 찾고 싶은 한
The world is not that big
세상은 그리 크지 않아
Even without a time machine
타임머신이 없어도
I can also find out
나도 알아볼 수 있어
How is she doing where she is?
그녀는 지금 있는 곳에서 어떻게 지내고 있나요?
but i didn't do that
하지만 난 그러지 않았어
I didn't go to her even once
난 그 사람한테 한 번도 가지 않았어
Because that's her choice
그건 그 사람의 선택이니까
She would choose to express it that way
그녀는 그런 식으로 표현하기를 선택했을 것입니다
We are in each other's life
우리는 서로의 삶 속에 있다
None exist
없음
So I’ve been living well like this until now.
그래서 지금까지 이렇게 잘 살아왔어요.
If it weren't for this car
이 차가 아니었다면
Or is this just an excuse I made?
아니면 그냥 내가 한 변명인 걸까?
Do you just want to see her?
그냥 그녀를 보고 싶나요?
Now that I’ve met someone
이제 누군가를 만났으니
So far
지금까지
Just treat it as temporary
그냥 임시로 처리하세요
I had a dream and passed by like this
꿈을 꾸고 이렇게 지나갔어
Anyway, that's what I'm supposed to do here
어쨌든, 그게 내가 여기서 해야 할 일이야
Don't interfere
방해하지 마세요
Things you shouldn't interfere with
방해해서는 안되는 것들
that dream
그 꿈
actually
실제로
in my dream
내 꿈속에
that
저것
I have something to tell you
당신에게 말할 게 있어요
elder brother
형
You said you had something to say
할 말이 있다고 했잖아
want to tell me
나에게 말하고 싶어
What crazy things are you going to say again?
또 무슨 미친 말을 하려는 거야?
Say it
말해
do you remember
기억 나니
The summer vacation when I was 13 years old
13세 여름방학
your first time
너의 처음
hit me in your room
네 방에서 날 때려
Fortunately
다행스럽게도
Mom has seen it
엄마가 봤어
How sad she must have been that day
그날 얼마나 슬펐을까
She was beaten by her husband all her life
그녀는 평생 남편에게 구타당했습니다.
But I have to watch
하지만 지켜봐야 해
You bastard beat up her only daughter.
당신 개자식은 그녀의 외동딸을 때렸어요.
What is this crazy woman talking about?
이 미친 여자는 무슨 소리를 하는 걸까요?
But is she too sad?
하지만 너무 슬픈 걸까?
He actually turned a blind eye and walked away.
그는 실제로 눈을 멀게하고 떠났습니다.
right
오른쪽
It happened countless times after that
그 후에도 수없이 그런 일이 일어났어요
Is it possible that I am a transparent person?
나도 투명한 사람이 될 수 있을까?
Even if I cry and shout
울고 소리쳐도
Said I was in so much pain and discomfort
너무 고통스럽고 불편했다고 하더군요
But in that home
그런데 그 집에는
It's like I don't exist bro
난 없는 것 같아 형
So I want my mother to watch
그래서 엄마가 지켜봐줬으면 좋겠어
let mom
엄마하자
have a look
보세요
Is your hand healed?
당신의 손은 나았나요?
What
무엇
It's all because you always like to drink
다 네가 늘 술을 좋아해서 그런 거야
will never get better
결코 나아지지 않을 것이다
Are you crazy
제정신이에요
How long have I been looking for you to come now?
나는 지금 당신이 오기를 얼마나 기다렸습니까?
Where is the umbrella?
우산은 어디에 있나요?
How are you going to go back when it's raining so hard?
이렇게 비가 많이 오는데 어떻게 돌아가실 건가요?
Have you got the money?
돈은 있어요?
Hey, if you treat me like this, my mother will never let you go.
야, 나한테 이렇게 대하면 우리 엄마가 널 절대 놔주지 않을 거야.
Hello
안녕하세요
Why don't you help me up quickly?
빨리 나 좀 도와주지 그래?
Lighter
거룻배
What the hell are you doing?
당신은 뭐 해요?
Didn't I say it would hurt? Damn it?
내가 아프다고 하지 않았어? 젠장?
Be more careful
좀 더 조심하세요
What are you doing
뭐하세요
that hand
그 손
Does it hurt?
그거 아프니?
how painful it is
얼마나 고통스러운지
What's wrong with my hands?
내 손에 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
What's wrong? What do you want to say?
무슨 일이야 무슨 말이 하고 싶은 거야?
This is it
이거 야
Sometimes I look inside this car
가끔 이 차 안을 들여다보곤 해
There will be a strange feeling
묘한 기분이 들 것이다
I know this sounds unreasonable, but
말도 안 되는 소리인 걸 알지만,
I always feel like what I’m looking at is
나는 항상 내가 보고 있는 것이 이렇다는 느낌을 받는다.
Things that shouldn't be here
여기에 있어서는 안되는 것들
It's okay. Just pretend I didn't say anything.
괜찮아요 그냥 아무 말도 안 한 척 해주세요.
It doesn't matter anyway, right?
어쨌든 상관없죠?
what does that mean
그게 무슨 뜻이야?
Police officer
경찰관
I have something to say
할 말이 있어요
Now start what I said
이제 내가 말한 것을 시작해 보세요.
Can you please keep it a secret for me?
나에게 비밀로 해줄 수 있나요?
If word gets out, I might really die.
소문나면 나 진짜 죽을지도 몰라.
no matter what you want to say
당신이 무슨 말을 하고 싶어도
I promise I won't let you get any harm done
약속해요, 당신에게 어떤 피해도 끼치지 않게 할게요
Cases that happened in the village
마을에서 일어난 사건들
I have
나는 가지고있다
saw the murderer
살인자를 보았다
I saw him kill someone with my own eyes
나는 그가 누군가를 죽이는 것을 내 눈으로 보았다
The murderer is my brother
살인자는 내 동생이야
It is said that
라고 한다
There was a murder in the village
마을에 살인사건이 일어났어요
was recovered from the victim at that time
당시 피해자에게서 회수됐다.
My girlfriend’s waiter’s matchbox
내 여자친구 웨이터의 성냥갑
and note
그리고 참고
Could it be
그럴 수 있을까?
this one
이 하나
I didn't mean to see it
볼 생각은 아니었는데
I just went to the toilet during the day
낮에 화장실만 갔어
Picked this up
이걸 골랐어
But why
그런데 왜
you will have this
당신은 이것을 가질 것입니다
No way
안 돼요
is this really yours
이게 정말 네 거야?
Just calm down and listen to my explanation.
진정하고 내 설명을 들어보세요.
Who are you
누구세요
- What's going on? - Listen to me.
- 무슨 일이야? - 내 말 좀 들어봐
What exactly are you
당신은 정확히 무엇입니까?
who is
누구야?
-Teacher- Liu Fanlong
-선생님- Liu Fanlong
teacher
선생님
Something seems to have happened to Shun Ai
슌아이에게 무슨 일이 일어난 것 같습니다.
You wake up
당신은 일어나
This is wrong
이건 틀렸어
Everyone is dead anyway
어차피 다 죽었어
Can it still be saved now?
지금도 구할 수 있나요?
Hae Kyung can't catch him
해경이 못잡아